LIN YANG

2619 Ferndale Ave #2, Ames, Iowa 50010. Cell: (515)-708-7003. Email: Jeremy.linyang@outlook.com

CAREER GOAL

To bring to your organization enthusiasm, dedication, responsibility, and good work ethic, combined with a desire to utilize my skills obtained through my previous work experience, my Bachelor of Science Degree in Civil Engineering and Master of Engineering Degree in Industrial Engineering.

EDUCATION

Iowa State University

- Master of Engineering Industrial Engineering
- Bachelor of Science Civil Engineering

Ames, Iowa, United States

January 2014 – Present GPA: 3.33/4.00

June 2010 – August 2013

GPA: 2.84/4.00

WORK EXPERIENCES

• Herland Worldwide LLC, Ames, Iowa

Program Executive

May 2014 – December 2014

Did Chinese barite market researches and analysis; looked for potential barite suppliers in China; represented the company in a professional manner; had on-the-spot investigation of barite manufacturing plants; negotiated with the suppliers on terms of manufacturing standards, delivery and payment; set up and maintained stable relationships with the selected Chinese barite suppliers.

• China Railway 21st Bureau Group Co., Ltd, Tianshui, Gansu, China

Internship

Jun 2013 – August 2013

Worked on the bridge construction project for high speed train at the engineering department; analyzed maps, drawings, bridge blueprints; worked with other surveyors to conduct engineering surveys with total stations at the construction site; made engineering drawings with Auto CAD; supervised the implementation of safety regulation at work site; checked the results of the engineering calculations.

• ISU Foundation Phone Call Center, Iowa State University, Ames, Iowa

Fundraiser

January 2014 - March 2014

Contacted alumni, parents and friends of Iowa State to update records, extend invitations, thank donors, provide updates about the university, and request gifts to support the scholarships, faculty, and programs; raised approximately \$300 in support of programs and initiatives at the university; had a thorough orientation and training course to sharpen the communication skills and lean about university programs before calling.

• Ames Asian Market, Ames, Iowa

Store Coordinator

October 2013 – January 2014

Assisted in inventory flow; attended to customers; cash register, managed and stocked merchandise; took responsibility for the store safety.

• Geotechnical Laboratory, Iowa State University, Ames, Iowa

Researcher

September 2012 – May 2013

Designed and installed experimental apparatuses for the research; worked with professors to explore new methods for Iron-based bio-cementation; conducted experiments; collected and analyzed data; wrote reports; developed solid research abilities and experimental skills.

SKILLS

Computer skills: Microsoft Office, Auto CAD, MicroStation, Solidworks and 3ds Max Language skills: Proficiency in English and Mandarin Chinese

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

• Chinese Students and Scholars Association

Outreach department executive

Coordinated sponsorships; connected and communicated with sponsors.

• International Friendship Connection Group at Cornerstone Church

Group co-leader

Planned and organized events with other co-leaders, contributed innovative ideas to the group, made event schedule.